<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-09-07T19:30:43-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Cheng Nie(聂成)</title><subtitle>The Website of Cheng Nie</subtitle><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Overcoming Challenges and Lessons Learned – My Boston Marathon Experience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/boston2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overcoming Challenges and Lessons Learned – My Boston Marathon Experience" /><published>2023-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/boston2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/boston2023/">&lt;p&gt;The Boston Marathon is a race like no other, full of excitement, challenges, and unpredictable weather. This year’s race was no exception. I’ll share my experience, the obstacles I faced, and the lessons I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-race&quot;&gt;The Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite suffering from a lack of training, I managed to complete the race safely, finishing in under 3 hours – not too shabby for just one month of preparation! It wasn’t my fastest race, but it was certainly one of the most enjoyable, as I took the time to pose for photographers and high-five the audience along the route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was glad to run with my buddy Harris Wu once again, and I’m grateful for his hospitality, which made my racing experience so much better. The weather was far from ideal, with rain at the start and pouring down just after I finished the race. Despite the wet conditions, I wore my trusty 2019 first-generation Vapor Fly shoes, which served me well throughout the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges-and-adjustments&quot;&gt;Challenges and Adjustments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the race, I faced several challenges and made some adjustments to my initial plan. I experienced pain in both of my middle toes and had belly pain on my right side starting from Mile 10. To fight against potential cramps, I stopped to drink Gatorade every 2 miles. I used 4 salt sticks, which helped a lot, although I didn’t take them as evenly as I should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also changed my caffeinated gel plan at mile 17. I took one CAF 100 and one CAL 100, eating the CAF 100 right there and the CAL 100 at mile 20. I took one more gel (CAL 100) at mile 21.5 and ate it at mile 23. Despite having diarrhea both on Sunday and Monday, I managed to finish the race without any major issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pre--and-post-race-routines&quot;&gt;Pre- and Post-Race Routines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the race, I had two days of 30-minute hot baths, which I believe helped my muscles relax and prepare for the race. I had a great night’s sleep before the race, thanks to my AirPods Pro Two and a helpful sleep audio. In hindsight, I’m glad I didn’t have dinner at a Chinese restaurant, as I worried that some seasoning might have caused further digestive issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-learned&quot;&gt;What I Learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boston Marathon experience taught me several valuable lessons that I can apply to future races:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always be prepared for the weather, bringing a raincoat if necessary and wearing sun protection, even on overcast days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that my gear is appropriate for the race conditions, such as having a long sleeve shirt for colder temperatures.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to incorporate glutes workouts and add more long runs and speed runs to my training routine, now that I’ve fully recovered from my IT band issue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be mindful of my nutrition before and during the race, and consider avoiding new foods that might cause digestive issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plan better for race logistics, such as finding accommodations near the finish line and arriving at the starting line earlier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boston Marathon was a memorable experience, full of challenges and valuable lessons. I’m proud of my performance, and I’m grateful for the support of my friends and fellow runners. As I look forward to future races, I’ll take these lessons with me and continue to strive for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/boston2023expo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/boston2023finish.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/boston2023medal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/boston2023time.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">The Boston Marathon is a race like no other, full of excitement, challenges, and unpredictable weather. This year’s race was no exception. I’ll share my experience, the obstacles I faced, and the lessons I learned along the way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Playing a Chinese song in Piano</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/moon-heart/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Playing a Chinese song in Piano" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/moon-heart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/moon-heart/">&lt;p&gt;The name of the song is The Moon Represents My Heart (月亮代表我的心). You can find Bon Jovi’s cover (Yes, he sang this song in Chinese) version of the song as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/as73B_sjhHc&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><category term="music" /><summary type="html">The name of the song is The Moon Represents My Heart (月亮代表我的心). You can find Bon Jovi’s cover (Yes, he sang this song in Chinese) version of the song as well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">For Students</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/student-letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For Students" /><published>2023-02-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/student-letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/student-letter/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve adapted this post from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fixedeffects.com/for-students/&quot;&gt;Professor Brad N Greenwood&lt;/a&gt; with his verbal permission at CIST conference in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;for-students&quot;&gt;For Students&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions-for-letters-of-recommendation&quot;&gt;Directions for Letters of Recommendation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am always happy to write a letter for outstanding students who I have taught in class. “Outstanding” does not necessarily mean students who earned an A. Attendance, participation, and humor are just as important, as is treating the classroom experience with respect. Academic integrity and professionalism are also things that matter a lot to me. I won’t write a letter for someone who falls short on these!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that writing a letter is time-consuming. To ensure that your letters get submitted on time, please note the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I require at least one month’s notice before letters are due. Don’t even ask for a letter with less than a month’s notice.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fair warning: if you claim to be in desperate need of a letter with less than one month before it is due, I’ll probably put something about poor time management in the letter!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will have to send me relevant materials, such as your CV and statement of purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I will also ask you to send me an organized list of the programs or jobs to which you are applying, including due dates and contact information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To help me write your letter, you must send me a half page document explaining why I would be a good letter-writer for you. Please detail how you contributed to my class, what you learned from me, and why you think the material you learned in my class will be useful for your future endeavors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most importantly, let me know how it goes. I am always interested to hear the outcome of your applications and am looking forward to updates!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><category term="work" /><summary type="html">I’ve adapted this post from Professor Brad N Greenwood with his verbal permission at CIST conference in 2022.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Maui Oceanfront Marathon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/maui-marathon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Maui Oceanfront Marathon" /><published>2023-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/maui2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/maui-marathon/">&lt;p&gt;Maui Oceanfront Marathon has a fun course, though it is not fast. The temperature was in the 70-80 range, and the humidity was above 60%. I finished this Marathon on 2023 January 15th in under 4 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the first face-to-face &lt;a href=&quot;https://hicss.hawaii.edu/&quot;&gt;HICSS conference&lt;/a&gt; after several virtual meetings during the pandemic. I registered for the conference early in September to learn what other researchers were working on. Also, it is in Hawaii!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I made the trip plan for the whole family, running a Marathon in Hawaii came to my mind. After a quick search, I found this Marathon that happens in mid-January on Maui island. It happens after the HICSS conference ends and before my semester begins, which means it is a “GO” for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After registering for this event, I received many funny emails from the organizer titled “Nags from MOM”; MOM is the acronym for Maui Oceanfront Marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We flew to Maui from Des Moines on December 31st, and I noticed my left knee hurt a bit when I moved the luggage. With the MOM in 15 days, I started taking Aleve as anti-inflammatory medicine and stopped running. After three days, the pain seemed to disappear, and I resumed hiking. The pain quickly came back, and I had to take Aleve once a day for another seven days. Two days before the race, I stopped the medication because I wanted to feel the pain. I planned to give up the race if the pain became too much to tolerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, my knee was OK going into the race. The race started at 5 AM, which meant we needed headlamps to see where we were going. It’s very humid and hot in Maui all year long. Therefore, it is necessary to start the race before sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I carried my phone with me for the first time during a marathon. Because I may need to give up the race before mile 26.2, and I would need my phone to call an Uber to take me to my hotel. For the first 21 miles, I was running at an OK speed. But I could not run for the last 5 miles. Since I figured I would be able to finish the race, I was quite happy to alternate between walking and hopping in the final 5 miles. In the end, I was surprised that I still finished the race in under four hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several notes for running this race:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You don’t need sunscreen if you can finish the race in 3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HMO insurance does not cover out-of-state medical providers. When I am out of state, it covers only emergency room visits. I should consider switching to PPO coverage if I need medical attention during travel.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My doctor told me it was a good idea for me to stop Aleve before the race. Or else I could seriously injure myself during the run when the painkiller numbed my nerve.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pace picture from Strava&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/maui2023strava.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Maui 2023 &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video from Releve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/raS0N_0oplI&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><category term="run" /><summary type="html">Maui Oceanfront Marathon has a fun course, though it is not fast. The temperature was in the 70-80 range, and the humidity was above 60%. I finished this Marathon on 2023 January 15th in under 4 hours.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My 2022 Annual Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/review2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My 2022 Annual Review" /><published>2022-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/review2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/review2022/">&lt;p&gt;Here is my annual review of 2022 to answer the following three questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What went well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What didn’t go so well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did I learn?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-what-went-well-this-year&quot;&gt;1. What Went Well This Year?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;families&quot;&gt;Families&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ping and I celebrated the 12th anniversary of our wedding. A relationship is not an easy thing. A great relationship takes consistent effort just like any great art.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ping will hopefully start her lecturer job in the marketing department at our school. She will graduate around 2023 summer and we both will be working for Iowa State University.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Michael skipped a grade this year. Michael was complaining that school was too easy at the beginning of the second grade. Ping and I thought he was bragging so we brushed him off. After a few weeks, Michael still thought the school was too easy. Then, we started talking to his teacher about the possibility of skipping the second grade. After some tests, it was clear that he was “over-qualified” for the second grade. Since Michael strongly believed that he should skip the second grade, Ping and I signed the paper to initiate the process. He was very sad about not being able to see his second-grade friends as frequently, but he was also super excited to see what third grade has to offer. Needless to say that Ping and I are both proud parents.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Both Ping and my green cards get approved in the fall. It’s a great relief that we don’t have to struggle to get visas to come to USA.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Information asymmetry is real. I learned that I should not talk about many things: traditional Chinese medicine, religion, or politics. I see no need to persuade others including my mom, my wife, and in-laws.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 submissions.&lt;/strong&gt; No papers got accepted this year. But I had 6 submissions in total, including some initial submissions and some revise-and-resubmit:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;JAIS: 2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ISR: 2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;POM: 1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;JMIS: 1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30 minutes daily challenge.&lt;/strong&gt; I spend at least 30 minutes per day on my research projects for 365 days. This is my attempt to curb my procrastination of delaying things till tomorrow. It has been quite effective. Setting this laughably small task helped me start working on my research every day. Most of the time, I spend more than 30 minutes. I remember I used the same trick to jump-start my running routine back in 2017. That year, I completed the daily challenge of running at least 3 miles.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap Research Grants.&lt;/strong&gt; I was awarded $6K from Ivy College of Business for research support in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/32578977&quot;&gt;37 books&lt;/a&gt; this year. Out of these 37, these are the five that I highly recommend:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/notes/four-thousand-weeks&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Four Thousand Weeks&lt;/em&gt; by Oliver Burkeman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/notes/crying-in-h-mart&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crying in H Mart&lt;/em&gt; by Michelle Zauner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/notes/will&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Will&lt;/em&gt; by Will Smith &amp;amp; Mark Manson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/notes/the-power-of-now&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Power of Now&lt;/em&gt; by Eckhart Tolle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/notes/project-hail-mary&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project Hail Mary&lt;/em&gt; by Andy Weir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York City for a week in June.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/Liberty2022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Statue of Liberty&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/Empire2022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Denver 2022&quot; title=&quot;He is maaaad!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statue of Liberty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Metropolitan Museum of Art&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running in Central Park with friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restaurants and Karaoke in Flushing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Empire State Building and World Trade One&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosevelt Island&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six national parks in 10 days in Utah and Denver in July.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/Arch2022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arches National Park 2022&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rocky Mountain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great Sand Dunes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mesa Verdi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canyonlands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black Canyon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chicago and Minneapolis in August.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Art Institute of Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Field Museum in Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Minnesota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hawaii Dec 31 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dec 31 in 2010 was when my wife and I had our wedding ceremony. It’s great that we can celebrate this wedding anniversary with our sons on a trip to Hawaii.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;running&quot;&gt;Running&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/Strava2022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Strava 2022 Summary&quot; title=&quot;Strava 2022 Summary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I Finished 2 Marathons: Grandma’s Marathon in Duluth, Minnesota and Omaha Marathon in Omaha, Nebraska. I did not break my record of 2 hours and 46 minutes for a full marathon, but I am happy to recover from the DNF (Do Not Finish) in &lt;a href=&quot;https://chengnie.com/boston2022/&quot;&gt;2022 Boston Marathon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I served as a half-marathon pacer on March 19th in the St Patty’s Marathon in Des Moines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pics/Grandma2022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grandma&apos;s Marathon 2022&quot; title=&quot;My running buddies from Ames&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;health&quot;&gt;Health&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COVID&lt;/strong&gt; In October, my wife, I, Jordan, and Michael all got COVID. Each of us took about 5 days to turn negative after the onset of coughing symptoms. Fortunately, our symptoms are mild.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asthma&lt;/strong&gt; I was diagnosed with mild asthma in April. It helped me understand why I coughed so much when I caught cold multiple times last year. I started taking some Asthma medicine and they are very helpful to keep my cough under control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running indoors&lt;/strong&gt; I used to be a hardcore outdoor runner; I ran outdoors even when it is -20ºF (about -30ºC). Since I learned that cold air might trigger my asthma symptoms, I move my running sessions to indoor tracks or treadmills when it gets freezing outside. So far, no coughing symptoms during the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eight hours of sleep.&lt;/strong&gt; Why we sleep by Matthew Walker helps a lot. Both my wife and I suddenly realized the importance of sufficient sleep. So now the routine for us is to do meditation together for 10 minutes and go to bed before 10 pm. It’s not 7 out of 7 days perfection, but we made it about 5 out of 7 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blood donation.&lt;/strong&gt;  I donated 500 ml (17 oz) of blood in July. It took me more than one month to fully recover. Due to the slow recovery, I would not recommend it to any active runner like me.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;piano-lessons&quot;&gt;Piano lessons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been two years since I started taking weekly piano lessons. My piano teacher Dr. Janci Bronson has been very effective in teaching me the basics of piano playing and in helping me master some Chinese pop songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-what-didnt-go-so-well-this-year&quot;&gt;2. What Didn’t Go So Well This Year?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An addiction to dopamine rushes.&lt;/strong&gt; This is still an issue from time to time. For example, when I feel bored in my office, I would close my office doors and start wandering around on Twitter or YouTube. Sooner or later, I would end up on some websites that I don’t feel proud to be at.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I need to talk to my mentor&lt;/strong&gt; I forgot to talk to my mentors this year. This is something I can improve for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-what-did-i-learn&quot;&gt;3. What Did I Learn?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Work of 30 Minutes help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest Resistance is denial. By denying the meaning of my work, I give myself no motivation to work. To counter such resistance, I start to put in 30 minutes each day to work on my research. 30 minutes are not enough to get me tenured, but those 30 minutes positioned me in the right direction. 30-minute research is a laughably small goal that I don’t fear starting. It helps me to get started on working on my papers each day. And, happily, most days I work more than 30 minutes on my research. I get this idea of working at least 30 minutes per day from my running habits. When I started running in 2017, I made a goal of running at least 3 miles per day. It’s not a huge goal for many runners, but it got me into Boston Marathon with such consistent effort. Even though I did not earn my tenure yet, I think this consistency in my work ethic is the key to success in my academic career too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To keep my office door open when I work at school.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another form of Resistance is distractions. The main distraction for me is YouTube and Twitter. If I start watching YouTube, it is very hard to stop. The engineers on the other side of YouTube can feed me non-stop entertainment all day long. The only problem is that I need the time to work on my research/health/family. So, just like last year, I do need to keep my office door open when I have an Internet connection. Knowing that someone passing my office might see my screen, I would be less inclined to go to YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><category term="Annual Review" /><summary type="html">Here is my annual review of 2022 to answer the following three questions:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Improve Your Job Talk</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jobtalk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Improve Your Job Talk" /><published>2022-12-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/talk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jobtalk/">&lt;p&gt;To err is human. We all make mistakes occasionally, but mistakes during a job talk may cost you a nice job offer. Here are some tips for delivering a good job talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;know-the-time&quot;&gt;Know the time.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A usual job talk is 60 minutes to 90 minutes. Know ahead of time how much time you have for the job talk. The time you have will dictate how much detail you want to cover.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember how Google map allows you to zoom in or out on different map sections? In terms of managing your time, you also need to provide that function for your talk. Suppose the attendees asked many questions in the introduction section. After answering those questions, you should zoom out to give people a bird’s eye view of the literature and background so that you will have sufficient time to cover the results and contributions sections of your talk. Similarly, if not many questions are asked, you should zoom in on some challenging topics to show how much work you have done and why they are important for your research.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some new Ph.D. students might keep asking you about technical details that are not your main contributions. Some professors do that too. To make time for you to cover the main work you have done. You should move such conversations out of your previous job talk time. For example, you can say something like: I’d be happy to talk about this offline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;check-for-typos-in-slides&quot;&gt;Check for typos in slides.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you give a talk at school ABC, you can leave the ABC’s logo or school name out of your slides. If you include those, please make sure it is the right name and logo, not the name and logo of the previous school you visited yesterday.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The same applies to the date of the presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use Grammarly, ChatGPT, or your friends, or hire copy editors to proofread your slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-clean-slides&quot;&gt;Use clean slides.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use bullet points instead of long sentences in your slides. When your slides are crowded, they compete for the audience’s attention. People cannot listen and read simultaneously, so they won’t hear what you say when they read your wordy slides.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a page number on your slides. It is easier for others to ask questions like: “Can you please go back to page 19?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I understand some slides have to be crowded, like the results tables. Use animations on those crowded slides to help guide people’s attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ask-questions&quot;&gt;Ask questions.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treat it as a discussion instead of a lecture. Don’t rush to cover too much content. Take time to make sure the audience gets what you want to cover. For example, you can ask, “Is this point clear?” and encourage the attendee to ask questions by pausing at some critical points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-your-body-language&quot;&gt;Use your body language.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use open gestures and big movements. Please don’t put your hand(s) in your pocket or cross your arms on your chest. Because showing your palms tells the audience that you have nothing to hide. After all, you need the attendee to trust your message so that they want to be your colleagues in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video record yourself to diagnose and correct distracting habits, like shifting your weight from leg to leg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-your-voice&quot;&gt;Use Your voice.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speak up. Too low a volume makes people feel sleepy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use some vocal variety. Again, speaking monotonically will not help you deliver your message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-familiar-with-the-school&quot;&gt;Get familiar with the school&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know the names of the people in the room. The department has a directory with their photos and names for your reference. During your whole-day interview, including your talk, address them by their first name. For example, you can say, “This analysis answers Cheng’s earlier question” instead of “This analysis answers his earlier question.” Even if it’s the first time you meet each other, addressing them by their first name shows that you have done your homework of studying their directory. Another benefit of addressing them by their first name, instead of Dr. so-and-do, is priming them to treat you as colleagues instead of students. Some fresh Ph.D. students tend to call another professor as Professor so-and-so or Doctor so-and-so. But you want them to hire you to be their colleague, not to hire you as a doctoral student.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test the devices before the talk. Survey the room for your presentation, visualize the beginning of your talk, and think about how you want to move. For devices, please have some backup plans. For example, please bring your own clicker, and know how to use your phone or iPad to remotely control the presentation mode. Keynote slides on Mac are beautiful, but many schools may need a USB-C to HDMI connector to load the slides from your Mac. You might use Powerpoint or Google slides, which are more readily compatible. Besides saving your presentation file to a thumb drive, you can save it to cloud storage and share it publicly. You will need help remembering the long URL directed to your slides file. Therefore, shorten it using some service like bit.ly or tinyurl.com with some easy-to-remember alias. For example, I can shorten this dropbox URL: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/pvhzfmwabuqqjhf/blog_jobtalk.pptx?dl=0&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bit.ly/jobtalk2022&lt;/code&gt;. The short link will be much easier to remember and type on a computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><category term="work" /><summary type="html">To err is human. We all make mistakes occasionally, but mistakes during a job talk may cost you a nice job offer. Here are some tips for delivering a good job talk.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Boston Marathon Without Running</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/boston2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Boston Marathon Without Running" /><published>2022-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/boston2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/boston2022/">&lt;p&gt;Fifteen minutes before boarding the car to the starting line, I passed out. My doctor had suggested I take two puffs of albuterol sulfate before racing so that my mild asthma would not kick in during the race. When I passed out after one puff, I was confused about whether I was awake or asleep. Once I regained consciousness, I went to open my hotel room door and used a trash can to block the door so that it wouldn’t close. I grabbed my phone and was about to call 911 as I went to prone position. I crawled to the bathroom to throw up my breakfast and determine if I should call. After vomiting, I felt nauseous but nothing life threatening. I checked my Coros watch and it showed my heart rate had dropped to 65, rather than my usual 74. Then I told my friends to leave without me since I would not be able to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got back from Boston to Iowa Tuesday afternoon, I was so weak I lay on the floor of the airport gate for an hour before picking up my car. I still felt dizzy when I started driving. Before I got on the highway, I threw up everything into the Boston Marathon bag I had brought with me, then drove 45 minutes, straight to the urgent care before going home. The doctor there, Jessica, did an EKG, blood test, and COVID test. The COVID came back negative, the blood test showed mild dehydration, and the EKG showed some potential problem I could not understand. I was referred to the Emergency Room since the urgent care could not tell what exactly was wrong with my EKG reading. I spent three hours in the ER and another 17 hours in Mary Greeley hospital before I was discharged. Fortunately, they did not find any major concerns after a series of tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I threw up three times Monday and twice on Tuesday. The reason for my passing out and vomiting is that I went from horizontal to vertical too soon and held my breath while using the asthma inhaler. Both the sudden standing up and breath-holding caused insufficient oxygen flow to my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite an experience for my Boston trip. I was lucky it happened before instead of during the race. My English vocabulary expanded during this process as well. Here are two phrases I picked up after seeing a few doctors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vasovagal syncope:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;va·so·va·gal: | ˌveɪzoʊˈveɪɡ(ə) l, ˌvæsoʊˈveɪɡ(ə)l |: relating to or denoting a temporary fall in blood pressure, with pallor, fainting, sweating and nausea, caused by overactivity of the vagus nerve, especially as a result of stress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;syn·co·pe: | ˈsɪŋkəpi |: temporary loss of consciousness caused by a fall in blood pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orthostatic hypotension:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;or·tho·stat·ic: | ˌɔrθəˈstædɪk |: relating to or caused by an upright posture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hy·po·ten·sion: | ˌhaɪpəˈtɛnʃən |: abnormally low blood pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other lessons I have learned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try to share a hotel room with my running buddy if I race out of town.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I feel dizzy, lie on the floor while lifting my legs against the wall. This allows blood to flow quickly to the brain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I vomit, take small sips of water or Gatorade frequently for a few hours, then try eating easy-to-digest food like crackers or bananas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you remember what the Terminator said?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27ll_be_back&quot;&gt;“I’ll be back!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">Fifteen minutes before boarding the car to the starting line, I passed out. My doctor had suggested I take two puffs of albuterol sulfate before racing so that my mild asthma would not kick in during the race. When I passed out after one puff, I was confused about whether I was awake or asleep. Once I regained consciousness, I went to open my hotel room door and used a trash can to block the door so that it wouldn’t close. I grabbed my phone and was about to call 911 as I went to prone position. I crawled to the bathroom to throw up my breakfast and determine if I should call. After vomiting, I felt nauseous but nothing life threatening. I checked my Coros watch and it showed my heart rate had dropped to 65, rather than my usual 74. Then I told my friends to leave without me since I would not be able to run.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My 2021 Annual Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/review2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My 2021 Annual Review" /><published>2021-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/review2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/review2021/">&lt;p&gt;Learning from the author of Atomic Habit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/2019-annual-review&quot;&gt;James Clear&lt;/a&gt;, I plan to write an annual review of 2021 to answer the following three questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What went well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What didn’t go so well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did I learn?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-what-went-well-this-year&quot;&gt;1. What Went Well This Year?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;life&quot;&gt;Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I celebrated my 36th birthday this year. My father passed away in a motorcycle accident in May 1999. His life stopped at the age of 35.5 years before he could celebrate his 36th birthday. Therefore, my 36th birthday has always been a milestone in my mind. I am glad that I was able to celebrate it. Many times I wonder if my dad would be proud of me were he still alive. I hope to be alive long enough so that my kids will not have this lingering question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two of my papers were accepted for publication.&lt;/strong&gt; One was accepted for the &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Association for Information Systems&lt;/em&gt; in January and the other for &lt;em&gt;MIS Quarterly&lt;/em&gt; in December.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I completed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facultydiversity.org/fsp-bootcamp&quot;&gt;Faculty Success Program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; My school paid for this 12-week program that cost $4500. The goal of the program was to improve research productivity and life balance. I learned a lot from this program including time management, saying no, prioritizing projects, and finding mentors.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I won the &lt;strong&gt;Teacher of the Month&lt;/strong&gt; for Ivy College of Business in November.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/25513643&quot;&gt;31 books&lt;/a&gt; this year. Out of these 31, there are five that I highly recommend:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The School of Life: An Emotional Education&lt;/em&gt; by Alain de Botton&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1000 Years of Joys and Sorrows&lt;/em&gt; by Ai Weiwei&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The War of Art&lt;/em&gt; by Steven Pressfield&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open&lt;/em&gt; by Andre Agassi&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/em&gt; by James Clear&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My family and I went on a vacation to Florida in May to celebrate my elder son’s birthday. Legoland, Universal studio, and Gatorland were a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My family and I went on another trip to Dallas and Austin in December. It was nice to be back in Texas. During our six years (2012–2018) in Dallas, we had never been to Austin. Fortunately, this year’s annual conference for our area was in Austin, Texas and so we grabbed this chance. We also drove to Dallas to visit several friends and to enjoy so many restaurants (Haidilao Hot Pot in Frisco was our favorite part of this trip).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I went on a trip to Boston in October for the 2021 Boston Marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;running&quot;&gt;Running&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/athletes/12995121/posts/19159354&quot;&gt;365 days of running&lt;/a&gt; covering 2,361 miles this year. That is about the distance from New York City to Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://boston.r.mikatiming.com/2021/?content=detail&amp;amp;fpid=search&amp;amp;pid=search&amp;amp;idp=9TGHS6FF144A69&amp;amp;lang=EN_CAP&amp;amp;event=R&amp;amp;event_main_group=runner&amp;amp;pidp=start&amp;amp;search%5Bname%5D=Nie&amp;amp;search%5Bfirstname%5D=Cheng&amp;amp;search_event=R#&quot;&gt;Boston Marathon 2021&lt;/a&gt;, I ran my personal record of 2 hours and 46 minutes for a full marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-what-didnt-go-so-well-this-year&quot;&gt;2. What Didn’t Go So Well This Year?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eight hours of sleep.&lt;/strong&gt; I aim to get eight hours of sleep every day. However, once I start using the computer in the evening, I often cut one to three hours from my target sleeping time. This is something I will work on in the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily meditation.&lt;/strong&gt; I used to do one hour per day vipassana meditation. Similar to cutting my sleeping time, I cut my meditation time this year as well. Cutting corners in meditation time has led to some negative impacts on my life. First of all, it is hard to put my anxious thoughts at bay if I wake up during my sleep. Second, I tend to be distracted by thoughts and urges during the day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An addiction to dopamine rushes.&lt;/strong&gt; Life can be boring, therefore, there are so many products that I tend to use to kill time. Among all my time sinks, the biggest category is social media including Youtube, Facebook, and Wechat.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was sick quite a few times.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I experienced migraine symptoms during our Florida trip in May. The flight was delayed by eight hours (Allegiant Air) and I was sleep deprived when we arrived in Florida at 3 am.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I went through five rounds of cold from August to December.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I had shingles in October.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-what-did-i-learn&quot;&gt;3. What Did I Learn?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I do not have to like research to be a productive researcher.&lt;/strong&gt; Even Andre Agassi hates tennis! But that does not stope him from earning all those grand slams. I used to have unrealistic expectations about research: I have to love research to be able to work on it. When I do not seem to find that love, I tend to digress to social media. What I learned is that this is a typical symptom of procrastination by denial. By denying the meaning of what I am working on, I give myself excuses not to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To keep my office door open when I work at school.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a commitment device that help me stay focused on my work. It would be embarrassing for my colleagues to find me watching funny cat videos in my office.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talking to a mentor really helps.&lt;/strong&gt; It is the same reason why counselling helps. You may have noticed how easy it is to find problems in other people’s lives but not your own. Talking to a mentor or a counsellor gives them chances to identify the problems in your own life. Even better, these mentors and counsellors are often people you trust. They help you come up with constructive plans so that you will make fewer mistakes and avoid common pitfalls. By talking to my mentor, I found out some of the projects I spent time on were hopeless. The conversation helped me prioritize what I should be focusing on in my research. Also, through my mentor, I came to understand the papers I publish also appreciate in value, just like the value of investment houses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting realistic goals.&lt;/strong&gt; I used to think that I can spend five hours on research six days a week. This created a lot of trouble for me. Sometimes, I followed a self-sabotaging routine of starting a day with social media. When I realized that I would not be able to spend five hours on research that day anyway, I would give up that goal and do whatever I like. In addition, during those productive days when I did log 4.5 hours on research, I still felt like a failure since I did not achieve that five-hour goal. Planning my week ahead by marking my calendars was very helpful for me to stay realistic. I was able to stay committed to what I wanted to achieve by reserving time slots for research, teaching, family time, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Cheng Nie</name><email>cheng@chengnie.com</email></author><category term="Annual Review" /><summary type="html">Learning from the author of Atomic Habit, James Clear, I plan to write an annual review of 2021 to answer the following three questions:</summary></entry></feed>